<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Onshape Developer Documentation on</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Onshape Developer Documentation on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onshape-public.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API Explorer</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/explorer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/explorer/</guid><description>We document all available Onshape REST API endpoints in our Glassworks API Explorer:
https://cad.onshape.com/glassworks/explorer/
This API Explorer site enables you to run API requests directly within its interface and provides the output from the API call. To try an endpoint in the API Explorer, follow these steps or follow along with the video below:
Open this public Onshape document in your browser: https://cad.onshape.com/documents/e60c4803eaf2ac8be492c18e/w/d2558da712764516cc9fec62/e/6bed6b43463f6a46a37b4a22 Open the API Explorer in a new browser tab: https://cad.</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/architecture/</guid><description>Design in Onshape typically beings with a document, which is the container that includes all content related to a specific design. All data in an Onshape document is stored in Elements. Part Studios and Assemblies are two of the most common element types in a design. Throughout the design process, creating versions can be useful for product development management while working on the “Main” workspace. See also:
The API Introduction page for information on how documents, workspaces, and elements are assembled into a URL.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/quickstart/</guid><description>In this example, we will call an Onshape REST API endpoint to send a document name to our console. Please note that the sample shown on this page is only designed to be used as a quick start guide and does not represent a full Onshape application.
System Requirements You must be signed in to your Onshape account at https://cad.onshape.com (or https://companyName.onshape.com for Enterprise accounts). This example is coded in Python.</description></item><item><title>Why Onshape?</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/whyonshape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/whyonshape/</guid><description>Why Onshape? As long as there have been applications that manage organizational data into a database, there has been a need to share that data between different departments and therefore, usually, different systems. In a typical design/manufacturing organization, there could be at least four or five mission-critical databases that manage the data for different departments and for different stages in the product’s lifecycle.
Initially, these systems provide the capabilities required by their consumers (i.</description></item><item><title>OAuth</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/oauth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/oauth/</guid><description>See the gltf-viewer-app for a working example of OAuth2.
📘 Note
All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store (Onshape Apps) must use OAuth2 for authorization. Automation scripts (or applications not meant for the Onshape App Store) may use either OAuth2 or API Keys for authentication. OAuth2 allows applications to call Onshape APIs on behalf of the users of the application; API keys will only perform operations on behalf of the Onshape user who generated the API keys.</description></item><item><title>API Keys</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/apikeys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/apikeys/</guid><description>📘 Note
All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store (Onshape Apps) must follow the instructions on the OAuth2 page and use OAuth2 for authorization. Automation scripts (or applications not meant for the Onshape App Store) may use either OAuth2 or API Keys for authentication. OAuth2 allows applications to call Onshape APIs on behalf of the users of the application; API keys will only perform operations on behalf of the Onshape user who generated the API keys.</description></item><item><title>Assemblies</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/assemblies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/assemblies/</guid><description>This page describes the APIs Onshape provides for working with assemblies.
📘 Notes
This page provides sample code as curls. See the curl documentation for more information. All Onshape API calls must be properly authenticated by replacing the CREDENTIALS variable in the curls below. See the API Keys page for instructions and the Quick Start for an example. All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store must authenticate with OAuth2. This documentation refers to Onshape IDs in the following format: {did}, {wid}, {eid}, {pid}, {otherId}.</description></item><item><title>Associativity</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/associativity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:28:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/associativity/</guid><description>Onshape does not expose a persistent ID for any of these entities. When the model changes, the ID may change. Therefore, Onshape provides an API to enable mapping IDs from a previous microversion to the current microversion. Assuming a simple case of maintaining associativity for a face, an abstract workflow might be:
Read the tessellated model data. Select the face of interest. Store the Face ID and Document Microversion ID for the face.</description></item><item><title>Billing</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/billing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:29:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/billing/</guid><description>This document describes APIs that will allow partners to interact with the Onshape billing system.
Please address questions to &amp;ldquo;api-support@onshape.com&amp;rdquo; for the fastest response.
Overview All billing is done through &amp;ldquo;plans&amp;rdquo; that are created in the Developer Portal. A “plan” has the following attributes:
Name (also called SKU) A unique (within your company) plan name Description A user-visible description of the plan Amount The cost of the plan (may be one-time or recurring, depending on the type) Type Monthly, One-time or Consumable Onshape defines three kinds of plans:</description></item><item><title>Configurations</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/configs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/configs/</guid><description>This page describes the APIs Onshape provides for working with Configurations.
You can use Configurations to create variations of entire Part Studios, Assemblies, specific parts and more. You can configure feature and parameter values, part properties, custom part properties, face and part appearances, and sketch text. Each Part Studio can have only one Configuration, but it can contain multiple Configuration inputs. The Configuration inputs you define for a Part Studio become options when inserting that Part Studio into an Assembly or Drawing.</description></item><item><title>Drawings</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/drawings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/drawings/</guid><description>This page describes the APIs Onshape provides for creating and manipulating Onshape drawings.
📘 Notes
This page provides sample code as curls. See the curl documentation for more information. All Onshape API calls must be properly authenticated by replacing the CREDENTIALS variable in the curls below. See the API Keys page for instructions and the Quick Start for an example. All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store must authenticate with OAuth2.</description></item><item><title>Features</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/featureaccess/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:37:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/featureaccess/</guid><description>This page describes the APIs Onshape provides for creating and manipulating features and the Feature List in a Part Studio.
📘 Notes
This page provides sample code as curls. See the curl documentation for more information. All Onshape API calls must be properly authenticated by replacing the CREDENTIALS variable in the curls below. See the API Keys page for instructions and the Quick Start for an example. All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store must authenticate with OAuth2.</description></item><item><title>Evaluating FeatureScript</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/fs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/fs/</guid><description>This page describes some of the APIs Onshape provides for evaluating FeatureScript.
📘 Notes
This page provides sample code as curls. See the curl documentation for more information. All Onshape API calls must be properly authenticated by replacing the CREDENTIALS variable in the curls below. See the API Keys page for instructions and the Quick Start for an example. All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store must authenticate with OAuth2.</description></item><item><title>Import &amp; Export</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/translation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/translation/</guid><description>This page describes the APIs Onshape provides for importing files to Onshape and exporting files from Onshape into different formats. We refer to the process of importing and exporting files from one format to another as translating the files.
Onshape provides several APIs to support this format translation. These fall into three categories:
Synchronous exports - Export Onshape content to glTF, STL, or Parasolid format. Asynchronous exports - Export Onshape content into a variety of other formats.</description></item><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/metadata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/metadata/</guid><description>This page describes the APIs Onshape provides for working with document metadata.
📘 Notes
This page provides sample code as curls. See the curl documentation for more information. All Onshape API calls must be properly authenticated by replacing the CREDENTIALS variable in the curls below. See the API Keys page for instructions and the Quick Start for an example. All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store must authenticate with OAuth2.</description></item><item><title>Response Codes</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/errors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/errors/</guid><description>This page details some of the response codes that may be returned by Onshape API endpoints. For each response code, we&amp;rsquo;ve provided a brief description of the response and recommended next steps.
Success (2xx) The client call was successful.
200 - OK The client call was successful. No action needed.
204 - No Content The client call was successful, and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to return in the response body. The empty response body cannot be parsed.</description></item><item><title>Extensions</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/extensions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/extensions/</guid><description>This page provides information for some of the more common options for embedding a third-party application into the Onshape interface. Onshape provides many options for embedding commands in various menus, fly-out panels, and elements. In this example, you will embed a custom web page inside a document’s right side fly-out panel. This interface will receive information from Onshape and push information from the panel back to Onshape, providing a complete, bi-directional integration scenario.</description></item><item><title>Client Messaging</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/clientmessaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/clientmessaging/</guid><description>Application extensions and the Onshape JavaScript web client need to communicate directly, calling across the iframe containing the application extension using post message.
Onshape Client Messaging examples can be split into those that are initiated from the application extension and those that are initiated from the Onshape client.
Messages from the Extension These Client Messaging examples can be initiated from the application extension:
Click/close flyouts events: Notify the Onshape client that the user has clicked in the application extension, which should cause Onshape flyouts (versions, history, uploads, etc.</description></item><item><title>Structured Storage</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/structuredstorage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:40:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/structuredstorage/</guid><description>Sub Elements Onshape provides application elements storage that is controlled by applications through the API. These elements allow a set of named sub-elements.
The application can make changes to sub-elements independently or in arbitrary groupings. Changes may be wholesale replacements, or may be deltas. When performing a delta update, the application may post a full version as well, which allows the api to return a smaller number of deltas for subsequent queries.</description></item><item><title>Webhooks</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/webhook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:44:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/webhook/</guid><description>This page describes the Webhook APIs Onshape provides for working with notifications.
Notifications are delivered to an application as an HTTP POST with a JSON body, which includes information about the identity of the registration request and information specific to the event and notification message.
Webhooks are an alternative approach to polling; instead of your application continuously asking Onshape for new information, webhooks automatically send a notification from Onshape any time an event you are subscribed to occurs.</description></item><item><title>Launch Checklist</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/checklist/</guid><description>This checklist brings together the processes you should follow to ensure your app is launched successfully. While all tasks must be completed to submit your app to the Onshape App Store, the task sequence provided here is a suggestion.
1. Understand quality expectations These are to ensure that the Onshape App Store remains a trusted resource and that quality is maintained Review the Quality Considerations page, and reach out to the Developer Relations team with any questions.</description></item><item><title>Testing Guidelines</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/testingguidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/testingguidelines/</guid><description>The purpose of this document is to help you get your application and App Store entry ready for QA testing.
Application Release Workflow (ARW) Each application submitted to the Onshape App Store goes through a series of stage-gates:
Starting state: Ok to deploy to limited visibility on Production (Beta testing) Ok to make Public Goal state: Application is Public To advance to the next stage, your application must pass testing, and your App Store entry must pass review.</description></item><item><title>Quality Considerations</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/quality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/quality/</guid><description>Core App Quality Onshape users expect high-quality apps. App quality directly influences the long-term success of your app in terms of installs, user rating and reviews, engagement, and user retention.
This page helps you assess the core aspects of quality in your app, through a compact set of quality criteria and associated tests. All Onshape apps should meet these criteria.
Before publishing your apps, test them against these criteria to ensure that they function well.</description></item><item><title>Sync Data and Metadata</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/sync/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/sync/</guid><description>The first business case is probably the most common, “How do I sync data that I create in Onshape with my ERP or PLM system?”. There could be many reasons why you would want to sync data between two different systems. Primarily Onshape is a system that creates new data. This data is created by designers as they perform their daily tasks. While the designer works primarily in Onshape, the actual data that they create does not exist in a vacuum, it is used by other departments, other processes within the organization.</description></item><item><title>Sync Releases and Revisions</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/releases/</guid><description>This tutorials builds off the Sync Data and Metadata tutorial. Please complete that one before starting on this one.
In this case, we’ll be looking at the ability for Onshape to sync its release data with an external system and for that system to send information back to Onshape with regards to released data.
This specific business case will look at what happens when you wish for a PLM system to control the release of data instead of Onshape having that control – this is in fact a common use case.</description></item><item><title>Generate Derivative Files</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/derivative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/derivative/</guid><description>This tutorials builds off the Sync Releases and Revisions tutorial. Please complete that one before starting on this one.
It’s clear by now that Onshape doesn’t use files to store its data, instead it is a data driven solution that is always up to date. Files are a snapshot in time that provide a view of the design at a specific point in time - such as at a release or version.</description></item><item><title>Create an Extension</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/createextension/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/createextension/</guid><description>In this example, you will create a custom web page (as shown in the image below) that is displayed in the right-hand fly-out panel. This interface displays metadata pulled from a third-party system when a part in Onshape is selected. This interface can also update metadata in Onshape through the Update functionality.
You can follow along with the steps below with this video: Define the extension This tutorials builds off the Generate Derivative Files tutorial.</description></item><item><title>glTF Viewer</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/gltf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/tutorials/gltf/</guid><description>The GLTF Viewer is a sample application that demonstrates:
How to fetch a glTF representation of an Onshape model How to create an app that runs as a tab inside an Onshape document OAuth2 authentication Use of REST APIs Use of document context The application is built using Express and is deployed on Heroku.
Refer to the gltf-viewer-app README for instructions on running this sample app.</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/changelog/</guid><description>rel-1.185 - released 2024-08-12 Updated all endpoints that return a user summary (createdBy, modifiedBy) have a new boolean property isOnshapeSupport for use to separate Onshape support employee activities. Updated all bodyDetails, tessellatededged, and tessellatedfaces endpionts (parts and Part Studios) to include errorEnum vales for detecting new mate position, curve pattern and Simulation material checks. rel-1.184 - released 2024-07-19 Updated API version to V8, (https://cad.onshape.com/api/versions), A new microversion will not be created when a document restore operation results in a no-op.</description></item></channel></rss>