<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– Onshape App Store</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/</link><description>Recent content in Onshape App Store on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Launch Checklist</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/checklist/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This checklist brings together the processes you should follow to ensure your app is launched successfully. While all tasks must be completed to submit your app to the Onshape App Store, the task sequence provided here is a suggestion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-understand-quality-expectations">1. Understand quality expectations&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>These are to ensure that the Onshape App Store remains a trusted resource and that quality is maintained Review the &lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/quality">Quality Considerations&lt;/a> page, and reach out to the &lt;a href="mailto:onshape-developer-relations@ptc.com">Developer Relations team&lt;/a> with any questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-sign-in-to-your-developer-account">2. Sign in to your developer account&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Sign in to your developer account at &lt;a href="https://dev-portal.onshape.com">dev-portal.onshape.com&lt;/a>, and ensure your developer account details are accurate. Contact our &lt;a href="mailto:api-support@onshape.com">API Support team&lt;/a> if you need assistance.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-authenticate-your-app">3. Authenticate your app&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Please refer to the &lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/oauth">OAuth documentation&lt;/a> for information on authenticating your app with OAuth2.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="4-build-your-app">4. Build your app&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While building your app, use the resources in this Developer Documentation and on our Glassworks API Explorer. We recommend familiarizing yourself with the following pages:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/">Introduction to the Onshape REST API&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/architecture">Onshape Architecture&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/">Onshape App Development&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/extensions">Extensions&lt;/a> &lt;!-- Susan move the videos to their pages -->&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-dev/clientmessaging">Client Messaging&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store">Onshape App Store&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="5-prepare-your-store-entry">5. Prepare your store entry&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Prepare the descriptions, promotional graphics, screenshots, and videos you&amp;rsquo;ll add to your store entry. Make sure you include a link to if required. Watch this video for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See the video below for a walkthrough:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://onshape.wistia.com/medias/tuhuzfi7we">&lt;img src="https://onshape-public.github.io/images/AppStoreEntryVideoCard.png" style="width:5in" alt="OAuth app creation video"/>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="6-run-beta-tests">6. Run beta tests&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the beta period, try to enlist at least 5 active testers to get feedback before making your app available to the general public.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>To find beta testers, contact our &lt;a href="mailto:onshape-developer-relations@ptc.com">Developer Relations team&lt;/a>, and recruit via the &lt;a href="https://forum.onshape.com/categories/developer-community">Onshape forum&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To give beta users early visibility, first &lt;a href="https://cad.onshape.com/help/Content/teams-enterprise.htm">create a team&lt;/a>, then ensure your app is shared with that team in the &lt;a href="https://dev-portal.onshape.com">Developer Portal&lt;/a>. See the &lt;a href="https://onshape.wistia.com/medias/5t1dwkspfo">Create a Team in Onshape video&lt;/a> for a walkthrough.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="7-determine-your-apps-price">7. Determine your app&amp;rsquo;s price&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve determined your monetization model, set up your price, billing, and other details. Billing should be tested, and to do so a staging environment is available. See the &lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-adv/billing">Billing API&lt;/a> page for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="8-sign-and-return-the-developer-agreement">8. Sign and return the developer agreement&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Email to the &lt;a href="mailto:onshape-developer-relations@ptc.com">Developer Relations team&lt;/a> to obtain yours.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="9-submit-your-app-for-final-testing">9. Submit your app for final testing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve returned the developer agreement, you can submit your app to the &lt;a href="mailto:onshape-developer-relations@ptc.com">Developer Relations team&lt;/a> for final testing. &lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/testingguidelines">This is a comprehensive functionality and design test.&lt;/a> During this testing period (expect up to a week, depending on complexity), changes to code are prohibited unless requested. At the conclusion of the test, you will receive one of the following notifications from our Developer Relations team:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Approved for release&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Approved for release with feedback&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Changes required before another round of testing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="10-integrate-your-support-systems">10. Integrate your support systems&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Whether you use Zendesk, Jira, or email support, we’ll help you determine and set up this integration. Contact the &lt;a href="mailto:onshape-developer-relations@ptc.com">Developer Relations team&lt;/a> to explore these options. This is the channel we will use to test your app and provide feedback.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="11-connect-via-slack">11. Connect via Slack&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Connecting directly with our Support, Tech, and Sales teams has proven to be valuable to app developers. This dedicated channel is simple to implement if you already have a paid Slack account. If not (or if you want to use the free version of Slack), we can add members of your team as guests to our account. Please contact &lt;a href="mailto:amagnin@ptc.com">Aaron Magnin&lt;/a> to establish this connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="12-final-check-and-publish">12. Final check and publish&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First, double-check you&amp;rsquo;ve done everything on this list. Now you&amp;rsquo;re ready to publish your app to the production channel! Send an email detailing &lt;strong>when&lt;/strong> you’d like this to happen to the &lt;a href="mailto:onshape-developer-relations@ptc.com">Developer Relations team&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="13-promote-your-app">13. Promote your app&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Start promoting your app with the &lt;a href="https://www.ptc.com/en/brand-guide/logos/onshape">Onshape badge&lt;/a> and by presenting it to our internal teams in one of the following ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To the Onshape Tech and Sales teams in a small meeting (~1 hour, Wednesdays at noon Eastern Time)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To the entire Onshape organization in a company-wide meeting (~5-10 minutes, Thursdays at 11am Eastern Time).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="14-encourage-reviews-from-users">14. Encourage reviews from users&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The value of reviews is not to be underestimated. Reviews give users an opportunity to provide feedback, and can also signal to others that your app is worth investigating.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="15-maintain-your-app">15. Maintain your app&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Continually fix stability and performance issues. Improving the user experience will result in more engaged users, higher ratings, and in turn, more success.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Failure to respond to customer tickets in a reasonable time will lead to the removal of your app from the Onshape App Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="16-increase-engagement-and-retention">16. Increase engagement and retention&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Aim to increase user engagement, retain and grow your audience, and earn more revenue by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Encouraging repeat visits with a nurture stream and training materials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrating more features from user requests&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Interacting with and understanding your audience via the &lt;a href="https://forum.onshape.com/categories/developer-community">Onshape forum&lt;/a>, social media, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="17-address-app-security">17. Address app security&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At some point, a prospect or user will enquire about your app&amp;rsquo;s security controls. To address this, we recommend that you understand SOC 2 Compliance requirements, and consider filling out the &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/artifacts/consensus-assessments-initiative-questionnaire-v3-1/&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;source=editors&amp;amp;ust=1686683388460627&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw2xq8zlODs3a7W2Y3jighnr">Consensus Assessment Initiative Questionnaire&lt;/a> (CAIQ). Onshape/PTC cannot and will not attest to your compliance. More on SOC Compliance can be found at the following links:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://us.aicpa.org/interestareas/frc/assuranceadvisoryservices/aicpasoc2report">AICPA.org&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System_and_Organization_Controls">Wikipedia: System and Organization Controls&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Testing Guidelines</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/testingguidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/testingguidelines/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The purpose of this document is to help you get your application and App Store entry ready for QA testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="application-release-workflow-arw">Application Release Workflow (ARW)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Each application submitted to the Onshape App Store goes through a series of stage-gates:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Starting state: &lt;code>Ok to deploy to limited visibility on Production&lt;/code> (Beta testing)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Ok to make Public&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Goal state: &lt;code>Application is Public&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To advance to the next stage, your application must pass testing, and your App Store entry must pass review.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kick-off-testing">Kick Off Testing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While completing the &lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/checklist">Launch Checklist&lt;/a>, you will need to use Jira to request testing and release for your application. You can initiate the following tasks from Jira:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Request application testing&lt;/code>: This puts your application in the testing queue. We will note when testing has started (&lt;code>in progress&lt;/code>) and when concluded, the ticket will be closed. The outcome will include notes and links to any issues generated (&lt;code>tickets&lt;/code>). This phase may include as many iterations as needed to get your application ready.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Request public (general) authorization&lt;/code>: We will note when testing has started (&lt;code>in progress&lt;/code>), and this request will trigger a review of your app store entry and any outstanding bugs. Note there is no implied testing of your application, simply a review of outstanding issues (&lt;code>tickets&lt;/code>) and of the App Store entry. Success at this stage will advance the Application Release Workflow (ARW), and you can request public release.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Request public (general) release&lt;/code>: This request states that you have coordinated with the &lt;a href="mailto:onshape-developer-relations@ptc.com">Developer Relations team&lt;/a> and the Onshape Marketing team&lt;!--How do they get in touch with the Marketing team? Slack?-->, and agreement has been reached that the app is ready for launch. Congratulations!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="testing-protocol">Testing Protocol&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Applications&lt;/em> are first tested against the checklist in &lt;a href="#addendum-a">Addendum A&lt;/a>. &lt;em>Production App Store&lt;/em> entries are then performed against the checklist in &lt;a href="#addendum-b">Addendum B&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Results will be viewable in your Onshape support system (i.e., Zendesk, Jira). The result of each test will be one of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Pass&lt;/code>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>No action needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No notification issued. &lt;!-- How do they know it passed? Does it just show up in the app store? -->&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Enhancement&lt;/code>: Suggestions we believe would make the application better.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Will NOT prevent the application from being turned on for public access.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Bug (low priority)&lt;/code>: Slight deviations from the criteria that have low end user impact.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Will NOT prevent the application being turned on for public access.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No stipulated time-frame for resolution.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Bug (medium priority)&lt;/code>: Material deviations from the criteria that are noticeable to the end-user. Represents a minor problem that requires a work-around.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Will NOT prevent the application from being turned on for public access.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Must be fixed within 30 days.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Bug (high priority)&lt;/code>: Significant deviation from the criteria.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>WILL prevent the application from being turned on for public access.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Bug (MUST FIX)&lt;/code>: Significant deviation from protocol or security violation.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>WILL prevent the application from being turned on for public access.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the application is already public, it may be temporarily suspended from the App Store.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="testing-notes">Testing Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Testing may be requested at any time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Testing is done on a first-come basis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When testing is complete (pass or fail), you go to the back of the queue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="addendum-a">Addendum A&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;font size="5">Application Test Criteria&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The application must use the Onshape OAUTH mechanism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The OAUTH must be against the correct stack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To be promoted to the Production stack, and hosted service must be on a monitored production server with worldwide 24/7 availability.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application should not generate any avoidable console (browser) errors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application should should provide one or more of the following options. The user should not have to leave the registration workflow to complete a pre-requisite.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sign in using the Onshape ID (account created silently on first use)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sign in with partner product account credentials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new partner account&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application must be capable of managing/displaying documents in excess of 20. The application must display reasonable performance when reading documents, workspaces, elements, and parts. At scale, an account may have thousands of documents, many with multiple workspaces and each with multiple elements. Suggested strategies include:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using a &lt;code>Next&lt;/code> button to load the next 20 documents&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using infinite scroll (loading the next 20 if the scrollbar reaches the bottom of the dialog)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Displaying the most recently-opened documents first&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Displaying a counter of documents/workspaces/elements read&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using progressive loading&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application should correctly list valid documents when &lt;code>per document app access&lt;/code> is turned on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application should correctly handle selection of versions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application should correctly handle selection of workspaces (branches).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application should correctly handle/display elements that are:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Part Studios that contain nothing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assemblies that contain nothing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part Studios that contain only surfaces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Part Studios that contain only wire data (e.g., helices)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application should appropriately handle revocation of a grant.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="addendum-b">Addendum B&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;font size="5">App Store Testing Criteria&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The application should have a descriptive name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application summary should be accurate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The redirect URLS should be valid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The iframe URL should be valid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;code>Grant&lt;/code> (permissions) request should be no more than is needed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;code>Application Type&lt;/code> should be correctly set&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team visibility should be set (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The category should be appropriate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The application description should be accurate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Sign-In URL should be valid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The pricing summary should be accurate
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>i.e., trials should not be listed as &lt;code>Free&lt;/code>; &lt;code>Free for xx days and then $xx/month&lt;/code> is more accurate.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All pay plans should have accurate descriptions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The support URL should point to a resource for help (the resource should NOT be an FAQ page, unless that page also contains one of the other options):
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Support ticketing system (e.g., Zendesk, Jira, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web page with a telephone number&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web page with an email address&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Forum&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The EULA link should point to an English Language EULA.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Quality Considerations</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/quality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/quality/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="core-app-quality">Core App Quality&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Onshape users expect high-quality apps. App quality directly influences the long-term success of your app in terms of installs, user rating and reviews, engagement, and user retention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This page helps you assess the core aspects of quality in your app, through a compact set of quality criteria and associated tests. All Onshape apps should meet these criteria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before publishing your apps, test them against these criteria to ensure that they function well. Your testing should go well beyond what&amp;rsquo;s described here; the purpose of this page is to specify the essential quality characteristics all apps should display, so that you can cover them in your test plans.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="functionality">Functionality&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These criteria ensure that your app provides the expected functional behavior, with the appropriate level of permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Area&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Permissions&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The app requests only the &lt;em>absolute minimum&lt;/em> permissions that it needs to support core functionality.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="compatibility-performance-and-stability">Compatibility, Performance, and Stability&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These criteria ensure that apps provide the compatibility, performance, stability, and responsiveness expected by users.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Area&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Stability&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The app does not crash, force close, freeze, or otherwise function abnormally.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Performance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The app loads quickly or provides onscreen feedback to the user (e.g., a progress indicator or similar cue) if the app takes longer than two (2) seconds to load.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Visual quality&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The app displays graphics, text, images, and other UI elements without noticeable distortion, blurring, or pixelation.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="security">Security&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These criteria ensure that apps handle user data and personal information safely.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Area&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All private data is stored in the app&amp;rsquo;s internal storage. &lt;/br> All data from external storage is verified before being accessed. &lt;/br> No personal or sensitive user data is logged to the system or app-specific log.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Networking&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All network traffic is sent over SSL.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="onshape-app-store">Onshape App Store&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These criteria ensure that your apps are ready to publish on Onshape App Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Area&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>App Details page&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The app’s feature graphic follows guidelines such as: &lt;/br>- The app listing includes a high-quality feature graphic.&lt;/br>- The feature graphic does not resemble an advertisement.&lt;/br>- The app’s screenshots or videos do not represent the content and experience of your app in a misleading way.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>User support&lt;/td>
&lt;td>User-reported bugs are addressed if they are reproducible.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="test-procedures">Test procedures&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These test procedures help you discover various types of quality issues in your app. You can combine the tests or integrate groups of tests together in your own test plans. See the sections above for references that associate criteria with these test procedures.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Type&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Core suite&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Navigate to all parts of the app: all screens, dialogs, settings, and all user flows.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Security&lt;/td>
&lt;td>- Review all data stored in external storage. &lt;/br>- Review how data loaded from external storage is handled and processed.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>