<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Onshape App Store on</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/</link><description>Recent content in Onshape App Store on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Launch Checklist</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/checklist/</guid><description>This checklist brings together the processes you should follow to ensure your app is launched successfully. While all tasks must be completed to submit your app to the Onshape App Store, the task sequence provided here is a suggestion.
1. Understand quality expectations These are to ensure that the Onshape App Store remains a trusted resource and that quality is maintained Review the Quality Considerations page, and reach out to the Developer Relations team with any questions.</description></item><item><title>Testing Guidelines</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/testingguidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/testingguidelines/</guid><description>The purpose of this document is to help you get your application and App Store entry ready for QA testing.
Application Release Workflow (ARW) Each application submitted to the Onshape App Store goes through a series of stage-gates:
Starting state: Ok to deploy to limited visibility on Production (Beta testing) Ok to make Public Goal state: Application is Public To advance to the next stage, your application must pass testing, and your App Store entry must pass review.</description></item><item><title>Quality Considerations</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/quality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/app-store/quality/</guid><description>Core App Quality Onshape users expect high-quality apps. App quality directly influences the long-term success of your app in terms of installs, user rating and reviews, engagement, and user retention.
This page helps you assess the core aspects of quality in your app, through a compact set of quality criteria and associated tests. All Onshape apps should meet these criteria.
Before publishing your apps, test them against these criteria to ensure that they function well.</description></item></channel></rss>