<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction to the Onshape REST API on</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction to the Onshape REST API on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API Explorer</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/explorer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/explorer/</guid><description>We document all available Onshape REST API endpoints in our Glassworks API Explorer:
https://cad.onshape.com/glassworks/explorer/
This API Explorer site enables you to run API requests directly within its interface and provides the output from the API call. To try an endpoint in the API Explorer, follow these steps or follow along with the video below:
Open this public Onshape document in your browser: https://cad.onshape.com/documents/e60c4803eaf2ac8be492c18e/w/d2558da712764516cc9fec62/e/6bed6b43463f6a46a37b4a22 Open the API Explorer in a new browser tab: https://cad.</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/architecture/</guid><description>Design in Onshape typically beings with a document, which is the container that includes all content related to a specific design. All data in an Onshape document is stored in Elements. Part Studios and Assemblies are two of the most common element types in a design. Throughout the design process, creating versions can be useful for product development management while working on the “Main” workspace. See also:
The API Introduction page for information on how documents, workspaces, and elements are assembled into a URL.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/quickstart/</guid><description>In this example, we will call an Onshape REST API endpoint to send a document name to our console. Please note that the sample shown on this page is only designed to be used as a quick start guide and does not represent a full Onshape application.
System Requirements You must be signed in to your Onshape account at https://cad.onshape.com (or https://companyName.onshape.com for Enterprise accounts). This example is coded in Python.</description></item><item><title>Why Onshape?</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/whyonshape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/api-intro/whyonshape/</guid><description>Why Onshape? As long as there have been applications that manage organizational data into a database, there has been a need to share that data between different departments and therefore, usually, different systems. In a typical design/manufacturing organization, there could be at least four or five mission-critical databases that manage the data for different departments and for different stages in the product’s lifecycle.
Initially, these systems provide the capabilities required by their consumers (i.</description></item></channel></rss>