<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authentication on</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/</link><description>Recent content in Authentication on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OAuth</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/oauth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:39:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/oauth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://github.com/onshape-public/app-gltf-viewer"&gt;gltf-viewer-app&lt;/a&gt; for a working example of OAuth2.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📘 &lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store (Onshape Apps) must use OAuth2 for authorization. Automation scripts (or applications not meant for the Onshape App Store) may use either OAuth2 or &lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/apikeys"&gt;API Keys&lt;/a&gt; for authentication. OAuth2 allows applications to call Onshape APIs on behalf of the users of the application; API keys will only perform operations on behalf of the Onshape user who generated the API keys.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>API Keys</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/apikeys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/apikeys/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📘 &lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All applications submitted to the Onshape App Store (Onshape Apps) must follow the instructions on the &lt;a href="https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/oauth"&gt;OAuth2&lt;/a&gt; page and use OAuth2 for authorization. Automation scripts (or applications not meant for the Onshape App Store) may use either OAuth2 or API Keys for authentication. OAuth2 allows applications to call Onshape APIs on behalf of the users of the application; API keys will only perform operations on behalf of the Onshape user who generated the API keys.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>API Limits</title><link>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/limits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onshape-public.github.io/docs/auth/limits/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When using the Onshape REST API, it is important to understand the usage limits in place to ensure reliable and consistent performance for all users. These limits help safeguard the platform and ensure equitable access to Onshape services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rate-limits"&gt;Rate Limits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onshape limits the number of API calls that can be made within a given time period to maintain optimal platform stability and performance. Specific rate limit values vary by endpoint, but exceeding the threshold results in an HTTP response status code &lt;code&gt;429 (Too Many Requests)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>